NILANGA VIRAJITH

LinkedIn | → Medium | → GitHub | → Portfolio | → nilangavirajith5@gmail.com | → +94 71 290 7285 | → Sri Lanka

Profile

Seasoned and highly competent **FullStack Engineer** and a **Technical Team Lead** with a proven skillset and **5+ years** of demonstrated history of designing & implementing enterprise software solutions.

Skills

Languages : JavaScript | Java | Python

Backend : SpringBoot | Node.js | Express.js | Serverless
 Frontend : Redux | Redux-Saga | single-spa

Databases : MySQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Oracle PL/SQL

Testing : Junit | Mockito | Jest | Enzyme

• Miscellaneous : AWS | Docker | CI/CD | SonarQube | Veracode | Github | Jira | Confluence

Professional Experience

Sysco LABS

Associate Technical Lead

Aug 2021 - Present

- Leading the design and development of enterprise-level applications using latest technologies like single-spa, React, Redux, Node.js, SpringBoot, and AWS to drive business functions of a fortune 100 company.
- Designed and implemented micro-frontends, scalable APIs, serverless applications, and scheduled jobs to cater to the internal business needs of Sysco and suppliers of Sysco.
- Leading the development of several products from identifying system requirements, managing dependencies with external teams, software implementation, setting up CI/CD, testing, and configuring alarms, monitors, and dashboards.
- Conducting code reviews, and mentoring developers on coding best practices and efficient workflows, substantially reducing technical debt and improving the code quality.

Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2020 – Aug 2021

- Implemented and managed several web applications, serverless applications, scheduled jobs to support business functions of Sysco.
- Introduced automated PR reviews with **Github webhooks**, **AWS CodeBuild**, **SonarQube**, and **Veracode** to ensure that no pull request is merged without passing the quality gates and security compliance.
- Set up cloud infrastructure to deploy micro-frontends, microservices, scheduled jobs, and for CI/CD pipelines.

CodeGen International

Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2020 – July 2020

- Implemented scalable APIs using technologies like **SpringBoot**, **JPA**, **QuerydsI**, and **Oracle PL/SQL** to drive business functions of a fortune 100 company.
- Implemented REST APIs to support the migration of application frontend from Java Swing to Angular.

Software Engineer

Jan 2018 – Jan 2020

• Implemented core business functionalities of TravelBox wusing Java SE, Oracle PL/SQL, and Docker.

Software Engineer, Intern

Jul 2016 - Jan 2017

Education

University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Bachelor of Science (Hons) in Engineering

Specialization – Computer Science & Engineering

Jan 2014 – Jan 2018

Projects

- Item Enrichment | React, Redux, Redux-Saga, single-spa, Node.js, AWS, Serverless, Jest, Enzyme A web application for vendors of Sysco to enhance their item portfolio which then can be used in other platforms that sell their items. I'm leading the design and implementation of frontend, backend, BFF, cloud infrastructure, and CI/CD pipelines.
- GS1 Service | Java, SpringBoot, AWS fargate

A cron scheduler to sync Sysco's product information daily from a third-party information repository. I deployed the application in AWS Fargate to minimize the infrastructure cost as the application only runs a couple of hours daily.

- C-SPACE | Java, SpringBoot, AWS
 - A web application for Sysco Associates to create price agreements. I was involved in performance improvement of the API by migrating the primary database from AWS Redshift to AWS RDS.
- Product Promotion | Java, SpringBoot, JPA, Querydsl, Maven, Oracle PL/SQL

A web application to promote travel packages between different environments. I implemented the backend APIs to support the migration of frontend from Java Swing to Angular.

- NTB mobile banking app | Ionic, AngularJS
 - A cross platform mobile application for core banking features. I implemented several core functionalities in the mobile application.
- Manipulation detection in stock trading | Python, AngularJS

 Implemented a machine learning model to detect stock market manipulations using information entropy of trading actions.

Leadership and Mentoring

- Project Summit Software Engineering Mentor responsible for mentoring and coaching interns and fresh graduates on technical and soft skills.
- Conducted multiple motivational programs in rural areas of the country to mentor and encourage young high school students.

Other Roles and Achievements

- Technical Interviewer Conducted 50+ technical interviews to hire Software Engineers and Interns.
- Ranked 4th in the district and 104th in the country in Physical Science stream of G.C.E Advanced Level examination 2012.